<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="trustin@apache.org">Trustin Lee</author>
    <title>Testimonials</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Testimonials">
      <p>
        Alex Burmester says:
        <blockquote>
          <p>
            We are using MINA at a telco to route low level protocol packets
            to a third party.  We already had a SOAP and also a CORBA interface
            but for speed purposes we are trying out a lower level protocol and
            we needed a gateway of sorts to route messages between our cluster of
            servers and the third party's servers.
          </p>
          <p>
            I had been planning on using NIO and some aspects of
            <a href="http://www.eecs.harvard.edu/~mdw/proj/seda/">SEDA</a> but
            finding MINA was a real treat as it saved a lot of time, is well
            written and gets more testing than our in house QA would be able to
            cover.
          </p>
          <p>
            The speed and stability of our app on top of MINA has been excellent.
          </p>
        </blockquote>
      </p>
      
      <p>Jean-François Daune says:
        <blockquote>
          <p>
            We use MINA to communicate with
            <a href="http://www.banksys.com/">Banksys</a> 'point of sale'
            terminals (Visa, Mastercard...) for technical management operations.
            (software upgrade, remote monitoring, log transfer...)
          </p>
          <p>
            So far, MINA has worked really well for us. We used
            <a href="http://gleamynode.net/dev/tl-netty2/docs/">Netty2</a>,
            and clearly saw the improvements in MINA. I like the MINA API
            more. MINA really makes it easier to write applications using NIO.
          </p>
        </blockquote>
      </p>

      <p>Luke Hubbard says:
        <blockquote>
          We are using it for the network layer of
          <a href="http://www.osflash.org/red5">Red5</a>, an open source flash
          server. At the moment we have RTMP and AMF working and hope to add
          more protocols in the future.  MINA's design and ease of use has
          helped us get a prototype up and running quickly.
        </blockquote>
      </p>
      
      <p>Thomas Muller says:
        <blockquote>
          What a fantastic API! Definately the best I've seen since
          <a href="http://gee.cs.oswego.edu/dl/classes/EDU/oswego/cs/dl/util/concurrent/intro.html">Doug Lea's Concurrency API</a>.
        </blockquote>
      </p>
      
      <p>Paolo Perrucci says:
        <blockquote>
          We are using MINA to build the network layer of our multiplayer
          game server at <a href="http://ludonet.leonardo.it/">Leonardo.it</a>.
          Using MINA, we implemented different protocols in a few days;
          Game and HTTP tunneling.  In the past, we used NIO, and the advantage
          of using MINA is evident; the MINA API is elegant and very simple to
          use.  Last, but not least, MINA have a really responsive support.
        </blockquote>
      </p>
      
      <p>Julien Vermillard says:
        <blockquote>
          I'm using MINA for supervisory control and data acquisition (SCADA)
          embedded application. It's used for several tasks; connecting
          supervision clients to the server, interaction of the server with
          different hardware (other SCADA systems, media stream matrix,
          programmable automaton, remote data aquisition systems), custom
          replication protocols for fail-over service. I found MINA when I
          started implementation using NIO and it was a great time saver.
          You can switch from RS232 to TCP/IP and add SSL connectivity easly.
          The stability and the support is really great. The code and the
          design are simple and efficient, so you can easly implement high
          quality protocol logic without bothering with all the NIO quirks.
          I didn't really tested the maximum performance you can get out of
          MINA, but all I can say is that MINA is running 24/7 with an amazing
          stability and I'm not afraid of using it in harsh evironement.
        </blockquote>
      </p>

    </section>
  </body>
</document>
